Let's go! Let's go!
Start her up! Start her up!
- Cops!Go,go!
- Fuck!
Let's go!
God!
Jesus fucking Christ!
THE FURY OF A PATIENT MAN
Afternoon.
What can I get you?
I'll get it.
You call the beer people.
You haven't called them yet?
What'll it be?
White coffee, please.
- Something wrong?
- No.
- Afternoon.
- What's up. Charo?
I left you a tray,
it's meatballs today.
- No, thanks, I had a bite.
- Everything alright?
Yeah, fine.
THE BAR
Two high and one low,
three, plus two pair, five.
Two of mine, seven bids...
Come on, one left.
If you put that low again
I'm outta here, man!
You're obsessed!
All the time!
- It's my hand. What can I do?
- Shut up.
- Can I take this?
- A short coffee.
- High and low, no looking.
- You've already had three.
Never mind, they're paying.
- Any pork scratchings left?
- Pork scratchings now?
- José?
- No,thanks.
Come on, pairs.
- Yeah.
- No.
- Pass.
All of them. Fuck it.
- Hit me.
- Son of a bitch!
Now who's bald?!
What do you want me to do?
Fucking nice! Whoah!
If you're no good at it,
go back to your plumbing.
- Your deal, fuck it!
- A fucking winning streak!
You've got two pair now?
Don't shit me!
José! What a thrashing
we gave them, eh?!
Hi! I'm leaving you
Lucky Luke here.
Wow! That's looks great!
He wanted to dress like a cowboy
and I can't get it off him.
Tell your dad what you asked me for.
What's up, José?
- Hi, Pili.
- What's my girl want?
- A miniskirt.
- A miniskirt?
I'm buying a leash for you!
C'mon, Daddy, I'm so cute.
- Anything else, José?
- No, thanks.
- Pass me my bag.
- Ok.
That hairstyle suits you.
Thanks.
Here.
Juanjo, the kids are staying.
Keep an eye on them.
Let's go.
- See you.
- See you, handsome.
Your sister looks sad.
She's got a temper,
she's real hard to put up with.
What we talked about yesterday,
the statement and all that...
Don't worry,
you'll have it Monday.
Thanks a lot, José.
I owe you bigtime.
You're taking a load off us,
my head's...
- It got tricky, huh?
- What did?
Your brother-in-law.
If it's not next week,
it'll be the one after.
What can we do? Nothing.
Right.
But my sister gets so nervous,
no one can handle her.
It'll be out of the frying pan
and into the fire.
You look like crap.
Hello.
Can't you sleep either?
I was finishing some stuff.
At two in the morning?
I've got no time.
There's not enough hours in the day.
I see you never stop.
You always look wound up.
Sure. I've got a lot on my plate.
But I don't like complaining.
Get on with it,
that's what we all do.
Not all of us.
THE FAMILY
Afternoon.
Hello.
Your aunt left you a bag
with a bottle and things.
She says she can never
get you on our cellphone.
She's invited you
to dinner with them.
Forgive me for meddling, José,
but I know you, okay?
You should get out more,
meet people, have fun,
-be with the family...
- Thanks, Charo.
Hey, José!
I thought you weren't coming.
I said: "It's late, he's not coming".
- I brought a bottle...
- You didn't need to!
José, you fag! Lucky you've come
or I'd have stopped talking to you.
- I got this for the girl.
- Really?
I won't kiss you
because I'm married.
But whatever you want,
I'm your man.
- You want a drink? Women?
- He's a pain when he drinks.
Come meet Pili's sister,
she just separated.
She's as big as an ox,
but nice and warm...
- Are you a moron, or what?
- But honey, is it true or not?
- Stop goofing around.
- I love you when you get mad!
You get all silly.
Get off me, you idiot!
It's so hot.
My bracelet's too big for me.
It'll fit when you're older.
Last year,
Rubén Gémez from 4B
gave me a bracelet
his ex gave back when they split up.
- You've already got boyfriends?
- I did.
But don't tell my dad,
he'll get mad.
- Do you have a girlfriend?
- No.
8 years in October.
After my brother-in-law's thing,
my sister wanted to move away.
And I met her here.
I think it was fate,
I got her pregnant straight away.
I've got Pili right here
in the palm of my hand.
That woman's done so much for me.
Sometimes I think:
"Am I missing out on
stuff with my buddies
and screwing up bigtime."
You know what I mean?
But then I get home
from working like a bastard
and my girl's waiting for me,
that's just the greatest.
I wouldn't change that for anything.
Your buddies are around,
they are what they are,
but family?
Family is blood, José.
That's the way it is.
You're a great guy. Shit!
You're really great.
Good evening and thanks for coming
to our daughter's communion.
It's so exciting for us parents:
her first communion.
Wasn't she beautiful?
No, stunning!
I don't care how much
the dress cost.
I love you all,
but especially you, honey.
Come on!
Hey, José, having a good time?
- Nice communion, huh?
- Yes.
Isn't it nice?
And how about Anita?
How does green suit her?
She looks pretty, huh?
And your brother-in-law?
Juanjo said he's out in a week.
Him? Do you want to ruin
the communion for me?
- Don't you get on with him?
- No opinion either way.
I don't even know him.
Everyone says he's a good guy.
Eight years he's been in jail.
He can't be that good, right?
I really love Anita, José.
I love her a lot.
Inside or outside of jail
he's been trouble for her.
You look a bit tense too.
Don't look at me like that, José,
we're not 15 years old.
And out of sight...
Hey, mum's the word.
Come here.
You listen to me.
What's wrong? Jealous?
You're so short!
That's better.
Where'd you come from?
How come you hang around
my neighborhood so much?
I like it.
You like what?
The neighborhood.
Get outta here!
You live in a fucking nice area
in a house that's...
The living room's bigger
than my whole place.
How could you like this?
I like it.
You do?
You're kind of weird.
What else do you like?
What do you do?
I rent out two flats I inherited,
a garage, a store.
The house in the village,
I'll never sell that.
Maybe Pili's got a point,
you're a catch.
Anyway, man,
if you've got any spare,"-
The house in the village,
is it your parents'?
It was.
Is it nice?
The usual, I never go anymore.
And...
what if I go with you
and fix up the place?
We could both live there.
I could take care of you.
You could wake me up
in the morning with breakfast.
And we could hang out
like this all day,
doing nothing else.
Well, you could take me out
to dinner sometimes.
Or I could bring you dinner in bed.
What?
What about your boyfriend?
And your girlfriend?
I don't have one.
How long have you been with him?
Since I was 16.
You've been alone a while, huh?
What's the time?
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to bug you, sorry.
I've been alone for 8 years,
since he went to jail.
I got pregnant during a visit.
I know.
Juanjo told me.
What did he tell you?
He was the only one caught
in a jewelry store robbery.
And that someone died.
And he didn't know
who they were,
they just hired him
to wait outside with the car.
Curro's not a bad guy,
he just keeps bad company.
Did you know them?
If I did, he wouldn't be inside.
Why did he do it?
Did you ever ask him?
He never talked about his stuff
and I got used to not asking.
Was he afraid
something might happen to him?
He takes what he's dished out.
Was he afraid
something might happen to you?
I'm all he's got.
He just wants me to be okay.
Did they threaten him?
Really,
do you want to keep talking
about my boyfriend?
I don't feel like it at all.
Honey...
- Wanna play with your cousin?
- Yes.
Come on, come to Mom.
Wait a second.
Quique, Silvia's guy, told me
there could be work in the garage.
I'll see him tomorrow.
Eat up. And stop watching TV.
You want me to turn it off?
I want to watch cartoons.
Like it?
Yeah.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Nothing?
I'm fine.
Don't give me that "I'm fine" shit.
What the hell's wrong?
Calm down, the boy's asleep.
Calm down?
Curro...
- Fucking hell!
- Curro.
Don't treat me like an asshole,
please don't.
What's wrong?
Do you love me?
What?
Of course I do, loads.
Then why are you crying?
It's weird.
What is?
You being here,
I'm used to being alone.
- Jesus fucking Christ!
- Curro...
Curro, please, calm down.
- Jesus fucking Christ!
- Curro...
- Stop shouting!
- I will if I fucking feel like it!
- No, you're in my home!
- Your home?
- What?
What? Eh?
Don't you touch me.
After all I've done for you...
I've tried to keep focused,
to be okay,
to keep my head together...
After all I've done...!
After all I've done for you...
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
- You, pairs.
- I got pairs.
- Pass.
- Well...
- What do I do?
- Call.
Bid.
Raise.
Five more.
- Make me happy.
- Unless I blow you under the table...
- Right, what do I do?
- Play yours.
- Mine.
- Sure.
Then all in.
All in?
Relax, I got a "dandy" here.
- Tell me what you got.
-"Dandy", he says...
- I'll have to call.
- No, wait. What have you got?
High it is. Kings.
Fuck that bluff.
I'm not bluffing.
Fuck it, you bastards!
Suck on that shit!
Are you an asshole?
Are you an asshole? You clown!
Is this guy an asshole?
You think you're tough? Fuck me!
- I'll punch your lights out!
- Hey, take it easy!
Fucking hell!
Don't you touch me!
Don't laugh at me!
Shut your mouth
and get back there.
Don't fucking touch me!
Get the fuck off me!
Are you stupid, or what?
Are you there?
I've got a proposition for you.
WRATH
This isn't Ana. I want to talk to you.
Can we meet up?
What the hell's going on here?
Why have you got Ana's phone?
That man there is my father.
And the woman they killed
was my girlfriend.
Who were they?
Tell me who they are.
- I don't know anything.
- Yes you do.
And you're going to tell me.
You don't want anything
to happen to your family.
Are you threatening me?
You can't threaten me, motherfucker.
God!
Fuck you to hell and back!
Where is she? Where?
I'll call back. I'm with this man
and I can't hear you.
Big kiss. Ciao.
I've got nothing to lose now.
And I'll do what it takes
to get you to tell me.
I just want to know who they are.
On the night shift a man
came in with his head split
because some lads mugged him
for 20 euros.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
Be careful anyway.
Wrist injuries can get complicated
if you don't look after them,
so the less you move it, the better.
This is in case
you want to report it.
You can take these
every 8 hours for the pain.
Come back in 2 days
if the swelling doesn't go down.
Thank you.
- The bathroom?
- Yes, first on the left.
Pili, it's Curro.
Have you heard from Ana?
Yeah, I'm fine.
No, listen to me.
If she turns up
or anyone mentions her,
call me, please.
You got that? Call me.
I gotta hang up, 'bye.
I want to talk to Ana,
to know she's alright.
They're alright.
See you later.
'Bye.
Help me find them and make sure
nothing happens to me first.
If anything happens to my wife
and son, I swear I'll kill you.
Can you drive?
I haven't heard from them in years.
They were from my neighborhood.
I needed cash
and they offered me that.
I just had to drive.
The first year,
one of them came to see me
in jail a few times.
Apparently he was still
living round the way with his mom,
but then I heard nothing from him.
What's his name?
Santh.
But they call him "Juni".
And the others?
Julito and Rober.
I knew Julito from playing football
when we were kids.
Rober was an older guy.
He'd been inside
a couple of times, I think.
In theory,
he had the most experience.
Talking will do no good.
I don't want any trouble.
Not with these people or anybody.
You won't have any more trouble.
Just take me to them.
Excuse me, are you from round here?
No, we're doin' a degree,
an Erasmus thing.
Do you know "Santi"?
They call him "Juni".
Juni... Santi... No fucking idea.
- Where's the gym?
- Boxing gym? Back there.
- Go look there.
- See you.
Excuse me,
are you from round here?
We're looking for Santi,
they call him "Juni".
Santi what?
- A guy from Seville.
-"El Triana"?
I don't know what he's called now.
He's a buddy, a local.
Short, bulging eyes,
talks like...?
Andalusian.
Jacin!
What's El Triana's name?
- What?
- Is he called Santi?
- Who?
- EITHana?
- Triana who?
- Give me shit and I'll fuck you up!
You and whose army, fatass?
Fucking hell!
Hey, what's Triana's name?
- Triana? Santi.
- Is he around?
I haven't seen him.
He'll be around.
Got a light?
Here comes the big shot.
Triana, some guys are looking for you.
Fuck me! Currito!
Fucking hell, Currito!
It's great to see you!
- How you doin'?
- Good, man.
- When did you get out?
- Two days ago.
You put on weight, huh?
Hey, how'd you find me?
- I went to see your mom.
- Shit. How is she?
Old.
You got style, motherfucker.
This is José, a buddy. Santi.
What's up?
Are you buddies from...?
From "the can" I mean.
Are you mute, or what?
Are you mute?
Is he mute?
- Is he mute?
- Yeah.
Can you talk "mute"?
- He's mute, not deaf.
- Fucking hell.
Sorry, man, sorry.
Let's get a beer.
Come on,
I'm going to the storeroom.
Quit staring, Jacinto,
you'll get all weird again.
What's up, cutie?
I spend my whole day here.
His face looks worse than mine.
- What's up, Triana?
- What's up, man?
Mariano doesn't like you
taking people down there.
They're not "people",
they're my friends.
They say it smells like shit here
because it's blocked,
but I lost my sense of smell.
They're cool, they're buddies.
- You got my candy?
- Here, candy.
- No strawberry?
- I'll give you what you like later.
Watch it, there's a dodgy step.
The dwarf fell the other day,
almost killed himself.
This looks like it.
This is it.
Make yourself at home.
Just don't touch the computer,
I'm busy with something.
Juani's sister put me onto
one of those jerk-off chat pages
and they rob you blind
if you don't watch out.
A beer here, another here...
Take a seat here.
Well,
to Cumin, to his freedom.
It's great to see you.
How you doin?
- Good,good.
- Well, well...
You know I'm workin' in La Baraca?
I'm workin', doin' this and that.
They even got me on the web page,
check it out.
You and I had some times
in La Baraca.
In La Baraca and other joints.
This guy and I used to
get shit-faced alright.
You got a friend here
for whatever, you got me?
What this man's done for me,
you wouldn't read about it.
He's got a friend for whatever.
You know it, or don't you?
- Yeah, man.
- Not "yeah, man". Yeah, Curro!
You got a friend in me,
whatever you want,
I'm with you to the death.
Shit, yeah!
I was too busy to see you
in "the can" more than once.
I was real busy,
I was like all over the place,
but I thought about you a lot
and whatever you want, you got it.
Whatever you want.
You don't have any "nose candy"
to celebrate?
No.
You look good, it's great
to see you. How's the family?
Good, good. It's all fine.
I heard you had a kid
while you were in "the can".
- Yeah, he'll be taller than me.
- That wouldn't be hard.
- Hey, listen up.
- Go ahead.
You heard from Julito and the guys?
That's what you wanted to know?
You wanted to know about Julito.
He went to live in the country,
his dad's hometown, in Segovia.
What's it called? "Lebrero"...
- Lebreles.
- Lebreles, that's it!
He's been there a while.
He just up and left.
And Rober?
Rober?
Didn't you hear?
Rober killed himself.
You didn't? I thought...
Rober crashed his car and died.
Just over a year ago.
I tell you what: fuck him.
He was a prick from when
he was born to when he died.
Why am I telling you?
You know alright.
Shit, look! I knew there was
a scrap left here.
You don't want any, right?
Dope's more your thing.
If you don't mind, I'll do it.
You could tell Rober was going
to end up real bad.
You don't know
what he did to me once.
I was minding 4 kilos of blow
in my mom's house
and he finds out
and comes round begging:
"Gimme a few grams to sell,
we'll split it".
I said no, no way.
Three days later, I'm on the street
and three undercover cops turn up,
built like tanks.
I acted casual,
but I was scared shitless.
These guys go and I say:
"Hold on... it's Rober".
So I call Rober and meet up
with him, like it's nothing.
Acting casual, I tell him a joke
and while he's laughing
that rat laugh of his,
I get him, bam,
a headbutt, broke his nose,
bleeding like a pig he was.
I grab his balls tight
and the guy bawls:
"I ain't done nothing".
I tell him: "You're a pig
and I'm branding you like one!".
No, no, no.
There's no water.
Go.
Dry yourself off.
- Where's Santi?
- Talking to his girlfriend.
-"Girlfriend", he says.
- He's got no girlfriend.
Probably jerking off
to your sister on the computer.
Imagine Triana as your brother-in-law!
Imagine Christmas Eve!
Open the door for me.
- Afternoon, Mariano.
- Get moving.
- Who are they?
- Friends of Triana.
- Who let 'em downstairs?
- I told them they couldn't.
SantL
Fuck Santi, I'm the boss here.
Where'd you get that sweater?
- From Santi.
- No gifts here, they cost a fortune.
- Where the hell is Santi?
- Downstairs.
Downstairs?
Tell him to get the fuck up here!
You guys drive me fucking nuts!
- Mariano, the guy in the sweater!
- Where are you going?
You stay put!
The sweater's 20 bucks!
Do I stutter?
- Fuck!
- Get outta here.
No fucking fighting here!
-20 bucks or take it off.
- We gave it to him.
- Then get him up here.
- Here, count it.
Get outta here!
And don't fucking come back!
How could you do this to me?
- How could you do this to me?
- Do what?
What I did is my business.
Your business?
Fucking hell! Your business?
I could've left you in there.
I'll take care of it.
I want to see my wife.
I've done what I had to do.
I haven't.
Pili, it's me.
From a booth, I can't find my phone.
Maybe the boy took it.
I've been calling all morning.
No, your place.
I don't know your cellphone number.
Okay, I'll take it down later.
Good, better, more relaxed.
Have you seen Curro?
Have you spoken to him?
What did you say to him?
I don't know what to do.
My head's going to explode.
I don't know, a few days.
It's nice here.
No, José's not here.
He went to Madrid to do some stuff.
Listen, don't tell my brother, okay?
Okay. Thanks.
YOU tOO.
'Bye.
You're so silly. Alright, see you.
Shall we go?
It was Juanjo, I put it on silent.
Third gear's loose,
you have to work the clutch.
- Take it to a garage.
- What?
You're teaching me to drive now?
Are you gonna fix my clutch?
- What are you doing?
- It slipped.
Don't let it slip, relax.
And turn on the lights.
- Stop here.
- What?
Stop here.
JUANJO: WHERE ARE YOU
AND MY SISTER?
- Good evening.
We want a room.
One each?
No, one. For the two of us.
- I've only got them with a double bed.
- That's fine.
ID, please.
Is one enough?
105.
The stairs are down the end
on the right.
Our wedding was three months away
when it happened.
When I got to the hospital
she was still alive.
They had her lying on the bed,
on pain killers so that...
And she didn't move.
I didn't recognize her,
she was so swollen up.
Her face was disfigured
by the beating.
But her eyes were open...
and she was looking at me...
I took her hand and she...
stared at me.
The doctor told me not to worry,
that she was unconscious.
But when we were alone...
she started to cry.
She was looking at me and crying.
Then, calmly, little by little,
she faded away, but...
that image...
stayed in my head.
I can't get it out of my head.
I need to go out.
Alright.
Juanjo, it's me. Juanjo?
Excuse me,
have you got a charger?
Is it a thin connector?
I don't have those.
Can I use yours to make a call?
It's very important.
I'll pay if you want.
Make it quick.
Sure. Thanks.
Sara.
Sarita, it's your uncle.
Put your dad on.
The battery's running low,
so listen.
No, Ana's fine. We argued
and she got all worked up.
Be ready in case she calls back.
In case she turns up, okay?
Listen, how do you know José,
your friend from the bar?
No, no reason.
No, I'm not thinking anything.
Be ready in case she calls.
Right, 'bye.
Eva, honey, two cigars.
Thanks, babe.
- Good evening.
Black coffee
with a dash of cognac.
I want to settle up.
-"Good morning".
- Yes, sorry. Good morning.
The key, please.
I'll get the car.
Feeling better?
Now you're worried about me?
I just want this to be over.
I understand you.
I don't want to think about
how much you've suffered all this time.
If it happened to me...
- Are you from Extremadura?
- What?
You've got an accent
from Extremadura or thereabouts.
No.
Can I ask you a question?
Did you sleep with her?
Are you really asking me?
Fuck!
Hi. Excuse me,
we're looking for Julio.
He came here to live
from Madrid three years ago.
I don't know, ask at the square,
they're coming out of Mass.
Okay. Thanks.
You're welcome.
- He's called Julio.
- As if there were no Julios here.
What about a surname?
There are lots here, son.
I don't know, he's from Madrid.
- From Madrid...
- It could be "Filipindfi",
but if that's all you've got...
Is he tall, blond, dark hair, brown hair?
There are lots, Maribel.
Aunt Luisa's Julio,
Julio from Trapale,
your cousin Juliete too...
- My aunt Marina's Julio, plus...
- Yes, Julio from Tagones.
10 or 12 of them.
Don't you have a last name?
The Lord be with you.
May the blessing of God Almighty,
the Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit,
be upon you.
- You may go in peace.
- Give thanks to God.
Happy holidays, everyone.
What are you doing here?
Nothing, I was passing through
and I wanted to say hi.
This is José.
Hello!
This is Curro,
a friend from the neighborhood.
What a coincidence.
Yes, my buddy and I were
passing through... This is José.
- Nice to meet you.
- Carmen.
She's my wife.
Are you in a team?
- What?
- The sweaters, I mean.
No, it's advertising.
A friend's gym.
Boxing.
Is that why you've got...?
From boxing?
No, I got attacked.
But it's nothing, I'm fine now.
Are you still living
in the neighborhood?
No, I've been away.
Where?
Traveling, a lot.
But outside of Spain?
That too.
Where have you been to?
Portugal, France...
France! Where?
- France. Paris mostly.
- Paris?
I lived in Paris for two years,
with my aunt and uncle.
Where did you stay?
We were in Le Marais,
near the Pompidou.
- Oh, you too?
- We lived together there for a while.
I love traveling, but I can't
drag him away from here.
He's afraid of flying!
Sorry!
Sorry.
We have to go one day.
Paris is pretty, isn't it?
Yeah, very.
We saw Santi.
He told us about Rober.
A friend of yours?
An acquaintance from the neighborhood,
he died in a car crash.
- Are you from there too?
- No, I met him later.
Like some more
or shall I bring out the meat?
Thank you.
What's going on, Curro?
Honey, help me with this!
We should talk later.
How's your family?
It's all good. I had a kid.
Yeah, so I heard.
We're going to be parents too.
- You're pregnant?
- Yes.
You can't see it yet,
but I'm 15 weeks,
so now I can tell people.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Yeah, congratulations.
We don't know yet,
but I think it's a boy.
- Yes. It's not the best time, but...
- How come?
- We're a bit tight for money.
- You're not working?
Not now. We've got some land
nearby that was her dad's.
It's got pigs, sheep...
I make what I can from it,
but it's just a patch of land.
But it's well looked after.
If you like, I can show you now.
I have to feed the pigs.
What do you want?
Why have you come?
To see you.
Don't worry, he knows everything.
What do you want? Money?
No. We're on a trip, I told you.
We stopped by to see you.
Stop here, Curve. Stop here.
Look, Curro,
I'm grateful to you for everything.
And I'm sorry.
But I don't want any trouble.
I'm nothing like what I was then.
- I know.
- I'm doing great now.
You've got my number now, right?
If you need anything, call me.
But I don't want any trouble. Please.
What are you doing?
Please, please. I'm going to be
a father. Please, I'm begging you.
Please! They told me
it was in and out,
that no one would get hurt.
He set off the alarm...
- Why did you kill them?
- I didn't do anything!
I was scared shitless,
I swear to God!
I told them to just go!
I swear! They didn't listen to me!
- You beat them to death, you fucks!
- I didn't do anything.
I was scared shitless, I swear to God!
- You beat them to death!
- I told them to just go, I swear!
The alarm went off,
Santi jumped on the counter
and started yelling,
then Juanjo went crazy.
Juanjoug;
Rober?
Rober didn't...?
Juanjo?
No!
Get in the trunk.
In the trunk.
What about Ana?
Come on, cut it out.
Stop it, that's enough!
JEWELRY STORE
Pili, it's me.
Is my brother there?
Can you come get us?
Where is he?
No, I'll call.
Yeah?
Where did you get to?
I've been calling you...
What?
What did you tell Pili?
Have you spoken to Curro?
Where are you?
THE FURY OF A PATIENT MAN